[monsters snarling]
[people screaming in panic]
[Beatrix] At last, my city...
my kingdom...
your Empress has returned!
[people screaming in panic]
[Nya]
It's too dangerous out here!
You all have to get to safety!
Thank you, Ninja!
Beatrix coming back
is our worst nightmare.
[Nya] H'yah! Ugh!
[Sora] H'yah!
Who could support her
after everything she did?
Bunch of weirdos.
[monsters snarling]
[Sora] Please work, powers.
Please work!
[Nya] H'yah!
[Sora] Ugh!
So much for trying that move
on Beatrix again.
For a free Imperium!
[Beatrix] Ah,
just who I was looking for.
How dare you seize power
in my absence?
[he struggles]
I didn't seize power.
I was elected.
I serve my people.
[Beatrix] You naïve child.
A leader doesn't serve.
A leader is served,
and you will watch helplessly
as I take back
my rightful throne.
No!
We'll be free,
or perish!
[Beatrix] Okay, then.
[screaming]
[Beatrix] You will all submit
to your Good Empress,
or be crushed!
[monsters snarling]
[Nya] Ugh! Ah!
[Sora] Aah!
[groaning in pain]
[♪♪♪]
Is that... Lloyd?
Stop using
the Weapon of Desolation!
[roaring]
[Lloyd]
You're playing with forces
you cannot understand.
Oh, I understand force
very well, Green Ninja.
What I don't understand
is this hideous
new dragon shape.
Oh, I didn't think you Ninja
could sicken me more.
[Lloyd]
Then you underestimate us.
Looks like
you've changed too, Beatrix,
for the worse.
Much worse.
That's "Empress Beatrix,"
and I am
what you forced me to become!
I survived the living nightmare
that is the Land of Monsters,
and no ninja, in any form,
will stop me now!
[Lloyd] H'yah!
[roaring]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪
[Cole grunts with effort]
[powers sparking]
[monsters roaring]
Aah!
I don't need saving!
[Kai] We all need saving
right now.
[snarling]
[Frak] H'yah!
Ugh!
[groaning]
H'uh!
[Riyu grumbles]
[snarling]
[Jay] Uh!
[Jay] Eat lightning!
-[powers sparking]
-[Jay] Hey!
What? Stop staring!
Aah!
I already feel insecure
about this as it is.
[roaring]
[Beatrix] That impact
would have crushed
any other mortal.
Your new form is repulsive,
but it is tough.
It still won't be
enough, though.
[Lloyd] I've changed much more
than my appearance.
I now understand my role
in this world,
my connections to everything
in the Merged La--
Ugh! Are you trying
to make me puke
with this spiritual garbage?
Just shut up and fight!
H'yah!
I don't care
about your connections.
I care about your destruction!
Yours and everyone
who opposes me!
H'yah! Ugh! Ah!
Raah!
[Lloyd] You will care
about my connections
when I defeat you with them!
H'yah!
[roaring]
[Nya gasping]
Wait... does this mean--?
Whoo-hoo!
Yaah!
[Jay] Yee-ha!
[Cole grunting with effort]
[Cole] Sorry,
time to end this dance!
[Frak]
Did you see that green light?
[Kai] That was way more
than light.
[Wyldfyre laughs]
Stop talking
and start blasting, Kai!
Whoo-hoo!
[Frak] Yeah,
but how did our powers--
[Wyldfyre] What did I just say?
-R'ah! H'yah!
-[Kai] I really missed her.
Fire!
[♪♪♪]
[Frak]
And I really missed this!
[thumping]
[Riyu groans]
[Riyu growl-talking]
[Cole chuckles]
You're welcome, buddy.
[Beatrix] Of course you Ninja
would try and steal
what is rightfully mine!
[Lloyd] You don't know
how dangerous that thing is!
What it can do!
[Beatrix] It's pretty clear
that I do know what it can do.
You're manipulating
unbalanced Source Energy.
It's incredibly dangerous!
[Beatrix] Indeed.
Dangerous to all who oppose me!
[Lloyd] H'yah!
[monsters snarling]
[Beatrix] Destroy him!
[monsters roaring]
[Sora] Come on!
We've gotta get you indoors!
Hi'yah!
[citizens screaming]
[snarling]
[Nya] All clear!
Go!
Yaah!
[Sora] How...?
[Nya] My powers came back!
[Sora] Hyah! Funny. Mine...
...are totally
working again too!
[Nya] Must be from
that green wave of power
Lloyd sent out.
[Sora] Lloyd comes back
looking like a dragon,
and makes our powers work?
He has a lot
of explaining to do.
[Sora] Come on!
[Lloyd] Yaah! Yaah!
[monster snarling]
[Lloyd] Yaah!
[grunting]
Raah!
[Nya] Hi-yah!
Yaah! Unh!
[energy ringing]
[Nya] H'yah! What's going on?
Your powers get all weird again?
[Sora] I don't think so.
I think her mech,
whatever she did to herself,
it's not technology anymore.
It's part of her, organic.
[Nya] Gross. H'yah!
Any other brilliant ideas--
-[blow landing]
[groaning]
[impact]
[Arin] Oh, uh, hi.
Looked like you were in trouble?
[Sora] Arin!
Oh, I was starting to worry
I'd never see you again! Oh!
[Nya] Where did you come from?
[monsters snarling]
[weapon firing]
[Nya] Zane?
[Sora] Euphrasia?
[Arin] On the downlow,
Zane's chopper is not as fast
as Lloyd's new wings.
[monsters snarling]
[citizens screaming]
[Lloyd grunts]
H'ah! H'yah! Y'ah!
[claws ringing]
[roaring]
H'yah!
Impossible!
[Lloyd] Yaah!
[claws slicing]
[Frak grunts]
Don't think
you were invited there!
H'yah!
[Cole grunts with effort]
[Cole] Hopefully that'll
keep 'em out for a while.
[Jay] Look!
Is that... Lloyd?
[Lloyd] Yaah!
[Beatrix] Your new powers
have some surprises?
Well... so do mine!
[rumbling]
[Sora] H'yah!
[Arin gasps]
[Nya] H'yah!
[gasping]
[Cole] That can't be good.
[Beatrix]
I will take back my kingdom,
or I will see it in ruins!
[monster bellowing]
[laughing maniacally]
[gasping]
[monster bellowing]
[Loyalist] I did not know
the Weapon of Desolation
held such power!
[bellowing]
[Lloyd gasps]
Nor I.
I wonder if Beatrix is indeed
still controlling it.
[Loyalist] I am certain
this was all part
of the Good Empress's plans.
[Lloyd roars]
[monster bellowing]
[Lloyd] Yaah!
[Kai] Lloyd!
[Kai] H'yah!
[Wyldfyre] H'yah!
[roaring]
[Jay] H'yah! Ah!
[Arin] Oh, this looks bad.
Really bad!
H'yah!
[blow landing]
-[roaring]
-Aah!
[Lloyd gasping]
[Beatrix] This vision
is what carried me
through the torment of my exile!
Crush him!
[Lloyd] Aah!
[gasping]
[heavy blow landing]
[Nya] Yaah!
[Zane] H'yah!
[Nya] There he is! Let's go!
[monster bellowing]
[Zane] H'yah!
[snarling]
[Zane and Nya yelp]
[grunting with effort]
[monsters snarling]
[cackling]
[monster snarling]
[Cole] Yaah! Yaah!
Yaah!
[Cole] Yaah!
What's up, Lloyd? Been too long!
Change your costume
or something?
[Lloyd] Still hilarious, Cole.
[roaring]
A dragon dares show itself
in my presence?
Rip that filthy beast to shreds!
[Cole] Hup! H'yah!
I should have destroyed you
when I had the chance, Ninja.
[Cole] I was literally thinking
the exact same thing,
but you wanted me
to watch your triumph.
How's that workin' for ya?
[monster snarling]
I will not be defeated!
[rumbling]
[energy ringing]
[bellowing]
No... don't push it.
[crumbling blast]
[bellowing]
[wheezing roar]
[Arin] What's happening to them?
[Sora] I-I don't know!
[Nya gasps]
[Zane] They took in
significant energy,
yet did not grow larger.
Aah!
[Nya] But they did get
a lot stronger!
[Sora] Aah!
[Arin] Ugh!
[bellowing]
[roaring]
[Lloyd] H'yah!
H'ah!
H'yah!
[grunting in pain]
[Beatrix cackles]
You deserve this, Ninja!
[Lloyd strains]
[Arc Dragon speaking]
Connection... Green Ninja.
Do not forget your true power.
[♪♪♪]
[roaring]
H'uh!
Haah!
Aah!
[♪♪♪]
[Nya]
Well, this is certainly wild.
Raah-ha!
[Kai] Yaah! Hah!
Kai became a dragon?
Why didn't I become a dragon?!
[♪♪♪]
[monster bellowing]
[Nya] Huh! H'yah!
[Frak]
Let's be anywhere but here!
[bellowing]
[Cole] Oof!
[Riyu growls]
[Kai and Jay] Yaah!
[Beatrix] No!
You will not rob me
of my divine status again!
[blow landing]
[Lloyd] I warned you
not to underestimate
my new powers.
Yaah!
[gasping]
[Cole] No! Don't touch that!
It makes Elemental Powers
go haywire!
[Arin]
Then I guess it's up to me.
[monsters growling]
[screaming] No!
Give that back!
[growling]
[Beatrix]
Only I deserve to--
[blow landing]
[grunting]
[growling]
You repulsive beast,
you are no match--
[yelping]
Aah!
So, how do I shut
this terrifying thing down?
[rock crumbling]
[Cole grunts]
Dr. LaRow, she activated it
by saying
some enchantment backwards.
Okay, how does that
help us now?
There was one final word,
but we have to say it forward.
Uh... Tungo-Ham!
Tungo-Ham!
[Arin] Not it!
No? Um, try Tanji... blab!
No... blub!
[Arin] Are you just
making up words now?
Ba vang naut...
Tan... gauv... Hab?
That's gotta be it!
Tangauv-Hab!
Oh, please be right,
please be right...
Tangauv-Hab!
[blasting]
[straining]
[Sora] Grab onto something!
[♪♪♪]
[Arin gasps]
You did it! [laughing]
Never a dull moment
in visiting your hometown,
is there?
[chuckling] Yeah,
we gotta stop visiting.
[both chuckling]
[♪♪♪]
[Arc Dragon gasping]
[roaring]
[♪♪♪]
[swirling whispers growing]
The Legendary Green Ninja
has succeeded.
[Wyldfyre] Unconscious?!
Aw... I guess it's not cool
to blast someone with fireballs
if they're unconscious...
[quietly] ...but we both know
you deserve it.
Arin, that was...
that was amazing.
I just held this thing.
It wasn't awesome
like becoming
freaking dragon people!
So, uh, any... explanation?
[Lloyd] Long story,
but let's just say
I finally know
what the True Potential
of the Green Ninja is.
To turn other Ninja
into dragons
but not me?
Hmph! Great. Just great.
[Lloyd] No,
it's to connect with others,
to unite
and understand the world
through their perspectives
and enhance their powers.
[Nya] That's why our powers
started working again
and you could turn us
into dragons?
[Lloyd] I...
I didn't expect
that part to happen,
but uniting with others
shares a part of ourselves
with them.
It's something
our enemies rarely do,
and it's clearly stronger
than I ever imagined.
[shots blasting]
We'd better
shut down the strays.
[Jay] Cole!
I haven't seen you
fight that awesome
since Shintaro.
Thanks! I di--
Wait, you have
your memories back?
[Jay] A bunch of 'em.
I can't believe you made a crack
in the monastery wall
that looked like noodles!
What? We both did that!
[Jay] Not how I choose
to remember it!
[♪♪♪]
Unh!
[Loyalist groaning]
[crowd cheering]
Wha-ho!
[cheering]
[Imperian] Percival,
we apprehended two more!
We have to find them all!
[♪♪♪]
[medical monitors beeping]
[breath wheezing]
[♪♪♪]
[Lloyd] It clearly has ties
to the very creation
of our world,
but we never heard of it.
How did Beatrix find
the Weapon of Desolation?
Beatrix?
It was all me!
She of course
would take the credit.
Yet you supported her.
So many of you did.
I can't for the life of me
make sense of that.
I'm well aware
of how unstable Beatrix can be,
but when she fell,
when Imperium fell,
I had nothing.
I was certain
if I helped her return,
I could keep her worst impulses
under control.
But Beatrix can't be controlled.
I-I'm not sure that's true.
I could not control her,
but I think...
I think somehow, in the end,
the Weapon was controlling her.
Where'd you learn
about this thing?
In a place
I could never find again.
I don't believe
it even has a name.
[telepathically]
Yes, I agree.
I see now,
with the realms combined,
your duty is not only to us,
but to the entire Merged Lands.
The role
of the Legendary Green Ninja
has evolved.
And I will live up
to this new mantle,
I promise.
Very impressive, Riyu.
[Riyu grunts]
[♪♪♪]
[laughter]
[smashing inside]
[Cole] No, it's my turn!
Y'ah!
-H'yah!
-[Jay] It's not your turn!
[Cole] You've been
playing for hours!
[Jay] It's not my fault
I'm better at this game
than you!
[giggling]
[struggling]
[Jay] Huh?
[can clattering]
Yeah, his dad was leading
the Explorers Club expedition.
Let me just say, again,
you should be so happy
your parents are amazing.
[Arin chuckles]
[knocking on monastery door]
Welcome
to the Monastery of Spinjitzu.
And who might you be?
Mom?
Dad?
[♪♪♪]
[growling]
Master!
I have collected another icon!
[roaring]
[♪♪♪]